Okay, so all dynamic time warping is doing is trying to align the samples
那么动态时间规整是为了调整
between two whistles we're comparing so that they best match up.
我们对比两次哨音之间的样本 这样它们可以最好地匹配起来
&gt;&gt; Yep,
— 没错
let's line up the two signals we are trying to compare on the x and y-axes.
我们在 x 轴和 y 轴上调整想要对比的两个信号
That will allow us to more easily see how we are matching the samples.
这可以让我们更容易地看到我们如何匹配样本
&gt;&gt; Okay, let's put the shorter one on the y-axis for convenience.
— 为了方便 我们把较短的放在 y 轴上
&gt;&gt; A match without any time warping would be a straight diagonal going
— 没有进行时间规整的匹配会是一条
from the lower left-hand corner to the upper right.
从左下方到右上方的斜向直线
But for the types of singles we're comparing, that would be rare.
但是对于我们对比的信号类型 这是非常罕见的
&gt;&gt; We know we have to start with the first sample in each signal.
— 我们知道从每个信号的第一个样本开始
In this case, they're both 0.
在这个例子中 两者都是 0
&gt;&gt; For the next sample in the x-axis, we have another 0.
— x 轴上的下一个样本 还是 0
Is it better to stay matched to the 0 in the shorter sequence or
在更短序列中维持 0 更好呢？
transition to the 5 in the next sample?
还是在接下来的样本中转变为 5 更好呢？
&gt;&gt; Well, there will be less difference if we stay with the 0.
— 其实如果维持 0 会很少存在差异
&gt;&gt; So we'll draw a horizontal line here indicating that we're matching the first
— 那么我们在这里绘制一条横线 表明我们首先匹配 x 轴上前两个 0
two 0's on the x-axis with the first 0 on the y-axis.
和 y 轴上的第一个 0
&gt;&gt; For the next sample we have a 2.
— 接下来的样本中我们得到 2
That still matches with the 0 better than the 5.
这仍然比 5 更好地匹配 0
&gt;&gt; So we continue the horizontal line.
— 那我们继续画横线
&gt;&gt; But then we go to 3 on the x-axis which matches the 5 better.
— 然后我们到达 x 轴上的 3 可以与 5 更好地匹配
&gt;&gt; So we transition up one on the y-axis to indicate that.
— 所以我们转向 y 轴的 1 表示这个
&gt;&gt; We're going to have several 3's in a row next on the x-axis.
— 接下来 x 轴还有几个连续的 3
How do we match them to the 5's on the y-axis?
我们怎么把它们与 y 轴上的 5 匹配呢？
&gt;&gt; Well, we're going to need a transition to the 2 and
— 我们需要转化为 y 轴上的
0 on the y-axis soon.
2 和 0
So let's make our transitions so
那么我们进行转换
as to keep us close to the diagonal line as possible.
使我们尽可能靠近直线
&gt;&gt; I get it.
— 我明白了
We're trying to match the values as closely as possible
我们试图尽可能接近匹配值
to minimize the error.
最小化误差
And if the values otherwise tie, we try to keep to the diagonal.
如果数据是连续的 我们要尽量靠近直线
&gt;&gt; Correct, the 3's will match the 5's pretty well.
— 对的 3 和 5 可以更好地匹配
And by the time we get to the 2, the 3 matches that even better.
我们得到 2 时 3 和 2 可以更好地匹配
When we get to the 2 and
我们在 x 轴上得到 2 和 1 时
the 1 on the x-axis, it'll match very well with the 2 and 0 up here.
可以很好地匹配上面的 2 和 0
And the 0 and -1 match the 0 pretty well.
0 和 -1 可以更好地匹配 0
&gt;&gt; Then we can match the -2, -3, -3,
— 然后我们可以匹配 x 轴上的 -2 -3 -3 和 -1
and -1 sequence on the x-axis to the 3, -3 on the y-axis.
和 y 轴上的 3 和 -3
&gt;&gt; And the rest of the long sequence, 0, 1, 1, 1, 1,
— 长序列的剩余部分 0 1 1 1 1
matches the matches the 1, 1, and 2 on that y-axis.
与 y 轴的 1 1 和 2 匹配
The last 1 has to match the last 2 to finish the process.
最后的 1 和最后的 2 匹配 结束这个过程
&gt;&gt; Now we can calculate the euclidean distance as before, but
— 我们之前可以计算欧几里得距离
this time we had better matches.
但是这次我们得到更好匹配
&gt;&gt; Yep, writing it out,
— 没错 写下来
we have the distance being the square root 0 minus 0 squared which is 0.
我们得到的距离如下 0 减去 0 的平方等于 0
Plus 0 minus 0 squared again, which is again 0.
再次是 0 减去 0 的平方还是 0
2 minus 0 squared is 4.
2 减去 0 的平方是 4
3 minus 5 squared which is 4.
3 减去 5 的平方是 4
&gt;&gt; I think we get the idea.
— 我认为我们理解了这个理论
&gt;&gt; Sorry,
— 抱歉
I always have to see these things written out to really understand them.
我还是认为这些内容写出来更容易理解
After a lot of scribbling, we get a distance of the square root of 34,
通过这些潦草的涂画 我们得到距离是 34 的平方根
which is approximately equal to 6.
约等于 6
&gt;&gt; That is less than half of the distances we calculated before when we
— 与之前我们用 0 填补较短序列相比
just padded the shorter sequence with 0's.
这次是之前计算距离的不足一半
&gt;&gt; Which shows the power of dynamic time warping.
— 这表现了动态时间规整的神奇之处
For situations where we know the signals we are comparing,
在我们了解所对比的信号情景中
we'll have some sections that are faster and
与各部分相比 我们有更快的部分
some sections that are slower compared to each other.
也有更慢的部分
DTW is a very useful tool.
动态时间规整是非常有效的工具
&gt;&gt; I see a problem, though.
— 不过我发现一个问题
&gt;&gt; What's that?
— 什么问题？